We're all about to lose our minds.
Saltburn is a drama, comedy, thriller film directed by Emerald Fennell.
Struggling to find his place at Oxford University, student Oliver Quick finds himself drawn into the world of the charming and
aristocratic Felix Catton, who invites him to Saltburn, his eccentric family's sprawling estate, for a summer never to be forgotten.
Oliver Quick, played by Barry Keoghan.
Felix Catton, played by Jacob Elordi.
Elspeth Catton, played by Rosamund Pike.
Sir James Catton, played by Richard E. Grant.
Venetia Catton, played by Alison Oliver.
Farleigh Start, played by Archie Madekwe.
Saltburn is a 2023 black comedy thriller film written, directed, and produced by Emerald
Fennell, starring Barry Keoghan, Jacob Elordi, Rosamund Pike, Richard E.
Grant, Alison Oliver, Archie Madekwe and Carey Mulligan.
Set in Oxford and Northamptonshire, it focuses on a student at the University of Oxford who becomes fixated with a popular,
aristocratic fellow student, who later invites him to spend the summer at his eccentric family's estate.
Saltburn premiered at the 50th Telluride Film Festival on 31 August 2023.
It was released in cinemas in the United Kingdom on 17 November 2023 and
in select cinemas in the United States on the same day.
The film had its US wide release on 22 November before its streaming release by Amazon
Prime Video on 22 December, on which it became one of the most-streamed films.
The film received generally positive reviews, and was nominated for
two Golden Globe Awards and five BAFTA Film Awards.
The film explores themes of suicide, karaoke, obsession, country house, maze.
The tone is intense and lighthearted and dark.